## **Poulima Biswas**

**REACT Fullstack Developer** 

## biswaspoulima36@gmail.com

+91 8939326005







React fullstack developer in Verizon with 8.5+ years of relevant industry experience. Primarily working in the **Agile** environment. Building Single-Page web applications with **React**, **Redux**, **Styled Components**, **NodeJS**, **Express**, and **MongoDB** while using **Docker**, **Kubernetes**, and **AWS** for code deployment. B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering from West Bengal University of Technology in 2015.

# **Key Skills**

React, Redux, Javascript, ES6, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB, Styled Component, Webpack, Eslint, Vite, Docker, Jenkins, AWS, Kubernetes

# **Work Experience**

**Verizon** - Dec-2018 - Present React Developer | MERN Stack Developer

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES - Sep 2015 - Nov 2018

Front End Developer

## **Projects**

## **VDS**

Verizon Design System is the single source of truth for Verizon's digital experience. It is a collection of reusable components and standards that can be assembled together to build any number of applications.

**Technologies:** React, Typescript, Styled Component, Lerna, Storybook, Jest, Rollup, Nodejs, MongoDB, Jenkins, Docker, AWS and Kubernetes

## Responsibilities:

- Convert reusable design components into reusable code components and maintain the
  performance, accessibility, and responsiveness to ensure that the design is implemented
  correctly in different contexts.
- Participate in code reviews to ensure adherence to design guidelines and code quality

Regularly audit the design system to remove redundancy and improve load times.

#### **WSR**

A report management tool which gives users a new experience in logging day to day tasks and helps the management to seamlessly track the efforts and productivity of resources, further improving business.

Technologies: React, Redux, Redux Saga, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB and AWS

## Responsibilities:

- Work closely with UI/UX designers to create responsive and visually appealing user interfaces
- Design and implement RESTful APIs for seamless integration between front-end and back-end systems
- Implement unit testing to ensure that each unit of the software performs as intended and meets requirements
- Troubleshoot, debug, and optimize code to ensure high performance, and reliability

## FrescoVibe

FrescoVibe is a blogging app like Medium powered by React/Redux. We have used Workbox for service workers and lighthouse for performance measurement.

Technologies: React, Redux, Redux Saga, SASS, Webpack, Bebel

## Responsibilities:

- Write well-structured code that is easy to maintain and understand
- Optimize code for performance, ensuring fast loading times and smooth user experience
- Ensure that the application is responsive and works consistently across different web browsers and devices

## Education

B.Tech - Computer Science Engineering (2011-2015)
West Bengal University of Technology

### **Achievements**

✓ Won spotlight award several times.

I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Bangalore Poulima Biswas